Ogous Chan Ali

hi@ogous.dev · ogous.dev · Komotini, Greece / Istanbul, Turkey

I am a senior full-stack software engineer focused on web development and blockchain. I have been providing scalable backend services and frontend development for over a decade. I specialize in Node.js and React/Next.js/React Native with Typescript and have worked on web3 for 3 years.

Technical Skills

JavaScript/TypeScript, Node.js, Ethereum, Polkadot, Arbitrum, Solidity, SQL, GraphQL, Express, Fastify, React, Next.js, React Native, Hardhat, Expo, AWS, GCP, Firebase, Amplify, Cloudflare, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, Nginx, RabbitMQ, Docker, Kubernetes, git, Jest, Cypress, Detox, IPFS, Ether.js/Web3.js/Viem.sh, Wagmi, HTML, CSS, Sass/Scss, Tailwind

Managerial Skills

Leadership, Ops/Project management, Project analysis, Budgeting, Investor relations, Recruiting/Interviewing, Performance reviewing, Documenting/presentation skills, Problem-solving, Negotiation, Critical thinking

Experiences

Senior Software Engineer

Superposition July 2024 - Present

A DeFi native Layer-3 (blockchain) focused on novel incentives and order-flow for growth and value capture, redefining utility and intent. *Adelaide, Australia*

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, Next.js, Node.js, git, Ethereum, Arbitrum, GraphQL

Senior Software Engineer

Triple O Games March 2024 - July 2024

Web3 gaming company building F2P/P2E games where players can own in-game assets as NFTs and earn rewards as cryptocurrency. *Canary Islands, Spain*

Achievements

- Designed the architecture of the backend of <u>Battle Derby</u> (Immutable zkEVM)
- Worked closely with <u>Immutable</u> team to implement solutions with their SCs, SDKs and APIs
- Developed cross-chain NFT tools like automation, migration, reward distribution
- Developed frontend dApps, launchpad, migrator etc.

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, Next.js, Node.js, Fastify, MongoDB, git, Docker, AWS, Ethereum, Solidity, ERC-20, ERC-721, Immutable zkEVM, GCP

Senior Software Engineer

Faculty Group Feb 2023 - Jan 2024

An investment group of blockchain space, offering solutions to support the growth of web3 companies, mainly on DEFI. Delaware, USA

Achievements

- Developed and maintained a <u>crypto market making tool</u> with distributed architecture. Worked with CCXT, CEX/DEX trading algorithms and Uniswap.
- Developed and maintained a <u>launchpad & liquidation tool</u> with staking, farming, NFT, ERC-4361, React, Hardhat, Walletconnect, Ethers, Viem, Wagmi.
- Provided services for B2B web3 clients, developed UIs and backend services: on-chain & off-chain synchronization and authentication, events/txs scrapers, token-liquidation & AMM tools, DEX/CEX adapters

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, Next.js, Node.js, Express, Fastify, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis, Socket.io, git, Docker, AWS, Ethereum, Solidity, ERC-20, ERC-721, ERC-4361, DEX, DEFI, Uniswap, Hardhat, Web3 APIs & tools

Lead Software Engineer

Capsule Corp Labs May 2022 - May 2023

Working as a venture studio operating on the twin company NTF blockchain Ternoa (Substrate-based Polkadot parachain). Biarritz, France

- Directed full technical decisions of client projects
- Managed a team of engineers
- Implemented creative solutions for bridging blockchain & javascript ecosystem
- Builded technical guidelines for clients and the company
- Promoted technology evangelism for fast growing ecosystem of web3
- Did performance reviews
- Assisted recruit new tech people

Achievements

- Led non-custodial crypto wallet project of Ternoa v2
- Contributed open source <u>SDK of Ternoa Blockchain</u>
- Deployed and launched 8 client projects with %0 failure rate
- 3 sold-out NFT marketplaces launches

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, Next.js, React Native, Expo, Node.js, Express, Fastify, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Socket.io, git, GCP, Ethereum, Polkadot, Solidity, ERC-20, ERC-721, ERC-4361, Hardhat, Web3 APIs & tools

Founding Software Engineer

Veganzone Oct 2020 - May 2022

A community based super-app for vegans and vegetarians. NYC, USA

- Developed full stack MVP, released and maintained
- Recruited and directed two engineering teams and a technical design team (10+ people, 3 direct reports)
- Planned and directed system migration to the highly scalable microservices architecture
- Managed the IT budget and technological complexity to efficiently align with business goals and strategy.
- Created quality assurance methods to keep functionality and performance and make it better
- Promoted innovation and increased motivation of teams and prevented operational inertia.
- Developed technical aspects of the company's strategy to ensure alignment with its business goals and board members
- Discovered and implemented new technologies that yield competitive advantage

Achievements

- Veganzone went viral in 24 hours, after release on stores
- Awards: Product Hunt Mobile App of 2021, #1 product of the day, #1 product of the week, #1 product of the month
- Invested with a valuation of 3M\$
- Crashfree rates increased higher than %99
- Tech budget decreased %45

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, React Native, Expo, Node.js, Fastify, PostgreSQL, Docker, Kubernetes, Redis, Socket.io, git, Github Actions, Google Pub/Sub, GCP, Cloudflare, Backblaze, New Relic, Grafana

Founding Software Engineer

Coffee.Digital Jan 2017 - Oct 2020

B2BC startup that enables customer engagement solutions for the brands in the coffee industry. Istanbul, Turkey

- Created a roadmap for business strategy and led the end-to-end technology planning process both strategically and tactically.
- Led and supported two teams (engineering and product)
- Monitor KPIs and IT budgets to assess technological performance
- Decided new technologies for market needs
- Designed and deployed a multi-tenant SAAS
- Builded a multi-tenant SAAS customer engagement system exclusive for coffee shops.

Achievements

 Achieved 400+ brands, 5k+ products, 4K+ daily unique visitors, 350K impressions monthly

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, React, React Native, Expo, Node.js, C#, git, ASP.NET, MySQL, AWS and Azure Devops

Senior Software Engineer

Anares Nov 2011 - Jan 2017

Software development agency, focused on providing end-to-end software solutions. Istanbul, *Turkey*

- Developed and deployed modern frontend projects
- Directed projects with kanban and analyzed business requirements
- Led frontend team and followed an innovation culture to keep operations competitive
- Designed and deployed CMS product for customers need
- Productized content management system for B2B digital publishers

Achievements

• Launched 100+ successful web & mobile projects

Tech Stack: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Typescript, jQuery, React, Ionic, C#, ASP.NET, MS SQL, MySQL, DynamoDB, MongoDB, Firebase, Amplify, Sentry, AWS, Azure, git, Jamstack

Education

Industrial Engineering, Yildiz Technical University, 2005-2009